waitroseflorist.com 2016-11-23

# Privacy And Cookies - Waitrose Florist

We use cookies to provide you with a better service. Carry on browsing if you're happy with this, or find out how to manage cookies.Close

To maintain your security you have have been logged out from Waitrose Florist due to no activity. [Sign in again](https://www.waitroseflorist.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/LogonForm?catalogId=10552&myAcctMain=1&langId=-1&storeId=10702)Close

Next day delivery when you order by 6pm Order in5 hours 38 minutes 

## Privacy and cookies

**Jump to...**

## How secure is your website?

Waitrose uses the latest technology to protect your credit and debit card details, and does not release personal information to any other company outside the John Lewis Partnership.

Waitrose uses the most up-to-date version of the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol to protect all the personal information you provide. This means that your information is encrypted and scrambled while in transit and cannot be read by anyone else.

By using these security methods, other visitors to the site are prevented from accessing or viewing your personal information at all times.

back to top of page

## What is your privacy policy?

Below, we tell you in detail how we use and store all of your personal and web-use data but, in summary, any personal information you give us is safe and confidential: we store all of your information on a secure server and never share any of your personal details with anybody outside of the John Lewis Partnership for their mailing or marketing purposes.

#### Your personal details

Your privacy is important to us, which is why we will never release your personal details to any company outside of the John Lewis Partnership for mailing or marketing purposes (although we reserve the right to disclose this information in the circumstances set out below). We treat all of your personal information as confidential and keep it on a secure server.

#### When we may use your personal details

To provide you with the best possible service, we’d like to keep you up-to-date with a range of products and services provided by the John Lewis Partnership including John Lewis, Waitrose and John Lewis Financial Services. This may include news of special events, promotions, product launches and catalogues. As we are constantly looking to improve our services, we may occasionally contact you for research purposes by post, telephone, SMS text messaging and /or email. You can choose not to receive further information from us by clicking the relevant boxes during registration.

You have the right to request a copy of any information about you we hold at any time, and also to have that information corrected if it is inaccurate. To view any information you have disclosed, contact:

The Company Secretary   
John Lewis Partnership   
171 Victoria Street   
London   
SW1E 5NN 

This does not affect your rights under the Data Protection Act 1998.

#### Using this website and your personal details

You do not have to provide any information to us to use this website. However, certain sections of the site or facilities within the site may not be accessible if you choose not to share essential information with us.

When you shop on Waitrose Florist we will ask you to submit, and will collect, personal information from you, including: your name, email address, billing address, delivery address, telephone number, product selections, credit card/other payment information, and a password. We, and our third-party advertisement and content providers, may collect information about your internet connection and website-use, e.g. the URL you came from, IP address, domain type, browser type, the country and telephone code where your computer is located, the web pages viewed during your visit, the advertisements you clicked on, and any search terms you entered on our website (User Information). We may collect this information from registered and unregistered users. We use this information to help us make improvements to our website and online services.

Any personal information you provide to us (or which is available on public registers) and any User Information from which we identify you is held in accordance with the registration we have with the Information Commissioner’s Office. We use your information for the following purposes only:

For statistical purposes to improve this website and the services we offer.

To provide you with relevant content and advertisements.

To administer this website.

If you have chosen during registration to receive notification of products or special offers that may be of interest to you, then we may use your personal information to send you these notifications by telephone, email or in writing.

Your personal information may be disclosed to other businesses within the John Lewis Partnership and to reputable third-parties who will help process your order. The John Lewis Partnership requires all such third-parties to treat your personal information as confidential and to comply with all applicable UK Data Protection and consumer legislation in place at any given time.

We may disclose your personal information and /or User Information if we are asked to do so by the police or any other regulatory or Government authority investigating suspected illegal activities.

back to top of page

## What are cookies and how do you use them?

So that you can make full use of the personalised features on our website, your computer, mobile phone or other device (all referred to here as device) will need to accept cookies.

Below you can see what cookies may be sent to your device by Waitrose Florist and what we use each cookie for. You can set your browser to reject cookies (see the ‘Help’ menu of your browser to find out how to do this), but please bear in mind that if you do this, certain personalised features of this website cannot be provided to you.

**Cookie Name** | **What we use them for**  
---|---  
s_sq, s_prop6, s_cc and s_vi | We use these cookies to see how many visitors use our website and which pages they view. We use this information to make improvements that make our website as usable as possible.  

WC_USERACTIVITY_{xxxx} | This cookie allows us to identify a logged in customer and their various preferences, such as preferred language and which product assortment is relevant to them. It helps us to personalise the website for each visitor.  

WC_AUTHENTICATION_{xxxx} | This cookie provides security when using the website: if a visitor has left their browser open and not logged out, this cookie will ensure that they are automatically logged out after 30 minutes of inactivity.  

WC_CartOrderId_{xxxx} | Stores the current active order reference number for the shopping cart.  

WC_CartTotal_{xxxx} | Stores the cart quantity, cart monetary total, currency, language, and quantity for wine mix and match purposes.  

WC_USERCONTEXT | Stores the user title, last name, postcode, number of previous orders, and hours/days since last order.  

WC_PERSISTENT | If a visitor selects the **Remember Me** option when logging on to the website, this cookie allows us to remember them when using the website at a later date from the same device. On returning, visitors will be able to view certain pages as if they were logged in, however if they view or change any personal information or checkout, they will be prompted to login.  

WC_SESSION_ESTABLISHED | This cookie is used to check we have stored a visitor's data in the secure fast-access part of our server. This ensures a faster website, which means a more efficient visit.  

JSESSIONID | As our website is split over several servers to improve performance, this cookie allows us to direct the visitor's requests to the same server each time, increasing the speed of the website.  

WC_USER_AUTHENTICATED | This cookie helps us recognise a visitor so we can display a welcome message.  

WC_GENERIC_ACTIVITYDATA | This cookie remembers the preferences of a guest visitor so that we can personalise the site for them when they return.  

LGP, TMP and TMS | These cookies show us how a visitor found our website and which website they came from. This helps us know which of our online marketing channels is most effective. They also allow us to reward some external websites for directing visitors to us.  

rememberUserLogonID | If a visitor selects the **Remember Me** option when logging on to the site, this cookie remembers the email address used. The website will show that email address in the login email address field on subsequent visits by the same visitor from the same device.  
  
**How to manage cookies**

Our cookies do not store financial information, or information which is capable of directly identifying you (such as your name or address). Cookies simply allow our website to retrieve this information in order to personalise and improve your experience of our website.

However, if you wish to restrict, block or delete cookies from Waitrose Florist, or any other website, you can use your browser to do this. Each browser is different so check the ‘Help’ menu of your particular browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

Please bear in mind that if you do this, certain personalised features of this website cannot be provided to you.

**Third-party cookies**

When you are on Waitrose Florist you may notice that there is content from other websites, for example a video from YouTube. We may also provide you with the opportunity to share information with others using social networks such as Facebook. We add this content from time to time to improve the user experience. As a result, you may be sent cookies from these other websites. Waitrose does not control these cookies and we suggest you check these third-party websites for more information about the cookies they use and how you can manage them. 

Some of the other business partners that may set cookies on Waitrose Florist include:

**Partner Name** | **What their cookies are used for**  
---|---  
Omniture | 

Our business partner Omniture uses analytics software SiteCatalyst to help us and them take and analyse visitor information such as browser usage, new visitor numbers, response to marketing activity and shopping times. This information helps us to make improvements to our website, the shopping experience and marketing campaigns.

The data stored by these cookies can be seen only by the relevant teams at Waitrose and Omniture, and never shows any confidential information.  

Edigital Research | 

Our business partner Edigital Research invites our visitors to take part in a survey of their experience when using Waitrose Florist. We use this survey to priorise our ongoing web improvements.

Cookies are used in this process to ensure we get a represenative sample of visitors for our research and that no individual visitor is unfairly asked to participate in the survey.  

Tagman Advertising

Accuen  
Affiliate Window  
Bing  
Criteo  
DoubleClick  
Google  
Google Analytics  
Monetate  
Responsys  
Specific Media  
Visual DNA  
Yahoo

| 

Waitrose Florist will sometimes advertise using an external company to deploy cookies from our advertising partners listed. These are used to help us and our advertisers see which advertisements visitors click on and interact with. Each individual advertiser uses its own tracking cookies and the data taken is not interchangeable. No confidential information is taken.

Our business partner TagMan provides a global Opt-Out function, whereby a user can visit [**tagman.com**](http://eu.tagman.com/index.php/consumerprivacy.html "visit TagMan.com") and switch off TagMan tracking.

If you opt out in this way for Waitrose Florist, you will also be opting out for John Lewis and all other TagMan clients. This opt-out facility is also cookie based, meaning that if you clear your cookie history within your browser, you would need to opt out again.  

Usablenet | 

Our business partner Usablenet use cookies to manage mobile sessions by monitoring idle times and enabling the full Waitrose Florist website on mobile devices, which can be used to implement links such as 'view full site'. The cookie will expire after 30 minutes or at the end of the session.  

Share Tools  | 

Where Waitrose Florist uses the opportunity to ‘share’ content with friends through social networks, such as Facebook, you may be sent cookies from these websites. Waitrose does not control the dissemination of these cookies and we suggest you check the third-party websites for more information about their cookies and to manage them:

Google  | 

Waitrose Florist may display video content using Adobe Flash Player. Adobe uses Flash cookies (also known as Local Shared Objects) to help improve the user experience. Flash cookies are stored on your device in much the same way as usual cookies, however they are managed by your browser differently.

If you wish to disable or delete a Flash Cookie, visit [**adobe.com**](http://www.adobe.com/special/products/flashplayer/security/index.html "Adobe.com")

Please bear in mind that if you disable Flash cookies for Waitrose Florist you may be unable to access certain content on the site.  
  
**Further information about cookies**

If you wish to learn more about cookies in general and how to manage them, visit [**aboutcookies.org**](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "aboutcookies.org").

**Website Recording**

Our web site may also use the SessionCam web site recording service. SessionCam is a product that has been developed by Service Tick Ltd. SessionCam may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, page scrolling and any text keyed into website forms. The information collected does not include bank details or any sensitive personal data. Data collected by SessionCam from the ServiceTick website is for Waitrose's internal use only. The information collected is used to improve our website usability and is stored and used for aggregated and statistical reporting. To find out more, visit [**servicetick.com**](http://www.servicetick.com/ "servicetick.com").

back to top of page
